Guide to the NYU Abu Dhabi Memory Project Collection AD.RG.023
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
- Office of Social Responsibility - Partner Interviews, OSR 10th Anniversary Project, 2021
  - Interview session with Bakht Munir Khan and Laura Assanmal (OSR) (10:08), 10 June 2021; ADRG023_066 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_066)
    Bakht is from Nowshera, Pakistan and works at NYU Abu Dhabi's Public Safety Office. He speaks English, Urdu, Pashto, and a little bit of Arabic. Before coming to NYUAD, he spent some time helping his brother with shopkeeping, but he was jobless. Then, he applied to a job position he saw in the newspaper, had an interview in Islamabad, and got accepted to first join the Officers' Club in Abu Dhabi, and then join NYUAD. He wants to spend as much time as he can in Abu Dhabi, giving his three kids the opportunity to receive quality education. Bakht is very connected to his family and takes care of his wife and kids every day. He really likes his position at NYUAD, as he is constantly learning something new from the students and staff. He has taken English classes, and started taking Arabic classes, but unfortunately they got postponed in March 2020. He is grateful for the opportunities to attend workshops and classes. His plan for the future is to give quality education to his kids, just like NYUAD students.
  - Interview session with Shihuabudeen and Laura Assanmal (OSR) (13:38), ADRG023_067 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_067)
    Audio-recorded session with Shihuabudeen, Light Driver, facilitated by Laura Assanmal, PPTP student. Conducted as part of the Office of Social Responsibility (OSR) 10 year Project/Memory Project Partnership.
    Shihuabudeen is from Kerala, India. He moved to the UAE in 2002, looking for better job opportunities and a better salary. He has switched workplaces, working at one company with his father in the fruits and vegetables district near Souq Mina, then working at another company in Abu Dhabi. Finally he began working at NYU Abu Dhabi. He has four children, the oldest one being in tenth grade. He recalls a memory over the course of 10 years at NYUAD, when he took some students on a trip. For the future, he hopes to bring his family to Abu Dhabi and offer them a better life there.
  - Interview session with Jeevan Puthiyaveetil and Laura Assanmal (OSR) (12:50), 24 June 2021; ADRG023_068 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_068)
    Audio-recorded session with Jeevan Puthiyaveetil, Driver at the Transport Department, facilitated by Laura Assanmal, PPTP student. Conducted as part of the Office of Social Responsibility (OSR) 10 year Project/Memory Project Partnership.
    Jeevan is from Kerala, India and he really likes the weather there. He works as a driver at the transport department of NYUAD. He has worked for 35 years of his life - spending 10 years in Saudi Arabia as a trailer driver, then in Dubai and Sharjah before moving to a position at NYUAD in 2011 through Global Wings. What made him change different job positions was usually the low salary. He came to the UAE in 1999. He is very thankful to NYUAD for giving him opportunities he never could have imagined - one of which is giving his children quality education. He is proud to say that one son is working in Dubai while the other studies medicine in the Philippines, at a U.S. university. With the help of the NYUAD salary, he was able to build a home back in India. He finished Business English 1 and 2 courses with the Office of Social Responsibility. Some of his dreams for the future are for his youngest son to finish his education and for his eldest to get a job at NYUAD.
- Remote Interviews with NYUAD Community Members [IN PROCESS], September 2021 - September 2024
  - Interview session with Wayne Young, Corey Meyer, Ross Jiang and Lauren Kata (Running Session 1) (56:52), 23 June 2021; ADRG023_063 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_063)
    Video-recorded session with former NYUAD Running Community Members - Corey Meyer (Class of 2015) and Ross Jiang (Class of 2020)- including Wayne Young, Director of Wellness recorded on Wednesday, June 23rd, 2021 and facilitated by Lauren Kata, Assistant Academic Librarian for Archives and Special Collections at NYUAD. Conducted as part of The Memory Project.
    In this interview session, the participants reflect on their journey to NYU Abu Dhabi and their experiences of building a compelling running community. They begin by sharing their first impressions of Abu Dhabi. Wayne and Corey reflect on the transition from the Sama Tower campus to the current Saadiyat campus, and subsequent changes in the athletics facilities including the indoor, outdoor tracks and a more sophisticated gym. Wayne and Corey also recall their initial struggle in building a running team, one reason being very few interested students. Wayne developed specific training programs and encouraged students in every way. Ross and Corey talk about their participation in different running events including the 10km race and Triathlon. Wayne emphasizes that over time he has built connections with different people in the UAE who invite and help NYUAD to take part in various events. Finally, everyone shares that the running spirit and team building was a valuable experience for them.
  - Interview session with Matthew MacDonald, Ramon Wrzosek, Alex Erdmann, Wayne Young and Lauren Kata (Running Session 2) (01:17:59), 23 June 2021; ADRG023_064 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_064)
    Video-recorded session with former NYUAD Running Community Members Matthew MacDonald (PE Curriculum Manager), Wayne Young (Director of Wellness), Ramon Wrzosek (Class of 2021) and including Alex Erdmann, former visiting scholar in the Computer Science department, on Wednesday, June 23rd, 2021 and facilitated by Lauren Kata, Assistant Academic Librarian for Archives and Special Collections at NYUAD. Conducted as part of The Memory Project.
    In this interview, the members reflect on their journey to NYU Abu Dhabi, and their experiences of building a compelling running community. They begin by sharing about their arrival and first impressions of Abu Dhabi. Then, they discuss how they met each other. They recall a SIG called 'On Your Feet' which helped and encouraged students to join the running community. Alex reflects on his intense running practice all across Saadiyat Island. Ramon considers running as a factor of sound physical and mental health. Matthew shares the growth of the running community over the years from 5-10 students to 30-40 students on track. At the end, they all share their unique experience of the Wadi Bih cross country race from their practice to participating and having a memorable finish.
  - Interview session with Suparna Mathur and Lauren Kata (01:30:27), 01 September 2021; ADRG023_065 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_065)
    Video-recorded session with Suparna Mathur, Director of Community Outreach (2013-2021), recorded on Wednesday, September 1, 2021 and facilitated by Lauren Kata, Archivist and Assistant Academic Librarian at the NYUAD Library. Conducted as part of The Memory Project.
    In this interview session, Suparna Mathur discusses being from Toronto, Canada. She has South Asian Indian heritage but she has spent the majority of her life in Abu Dhabi, UAE, as she grew up there, studying at the American Community School (ACS). The earliest stages of her career were in Toronto, where she worked in the non-profit and public sector, fundraising campaigns, and event management. Later on, she moved back to Abu Dhabi to start a non-profit group connecting community charities and nonprofits with community members, which prompted Ms. Renee Dugan, her supervisor, to hire Suparna at NYU Abu Dhabi, after being formally introduced by the CEO of Aramex. She was very excited for the opportunity, having heard of no similar project in the region. Suparna started out as having an ambassador role, connecting her corporate work with NYUAD's first few initiatives, but through time, this evolved to a full-time position. Throughout the conversation, she explains how NYUAD's recognition was cultivated through dinners, meetings with partners and helping students give back to the community. She highlights the program pillars: working with middle and high school youth (peer mentorship), deepening work with individuals with intellectual and physical disabilities, and working with migrant communities in Abu Dhabi, immersing in the UAE culture and heritage, and lastly, environmental sustainability, all designed at Community Outreach. She ends by highlighting the students' engagement and involvement in creating a greater community.
  - Interview session with Renee Dugan, Suparna Mathur and Lauren Kata (01:23:23), 19 Sept 2021; ADRG023_069 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_069)
    Video-recorded session with the members of NYUAD Community Outreach - Renee Dugan, Suparna Mathur, on Sunday, September 19th, 2021 and facilitated by Lauren Kata, Assistant Academic Librarian for Archives and Special Collections at NYUAD. Conducted as part of The Memory Project.
    In this interview, the members reflect on their journey and roles at NYU Abu Dhabi from its early days, and their experiences of building connections with a wider community/organizations. Renee shares her journey at NYUAD from its early days, starting as a Director of Admissions to founding Director of Community Outreach and current role as Associate Dean of Students and Director of Student Life. Similarly, Director of Community Outreach, Suparna, also shares about her experience working with NYUAD. Both reflect on their contributions and initiations in building a broad foundational network of NYUAD, approaching numerous academic and social groups/organizations and establishing NYUAD as a center for collaboration, especially regarding meaningful and sustainable engagement for students. Suparna recalls how Community Outreach worked hard to include a variety of volunteering opportunities and increasing their accessibility for students and staff. The two also shed light on how Community Outreach works collaboratively to prepare, plan, and execute programs keeping in mind the core mission of NYUAD and adding value to student life.
  - Interview session with Theresa Powell and Lauren Kata (01:20:45), 17 October 2021; ADRG023_070 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_070)
    Video-recorded session with Theresa Powell, Deputy Chief for People and Performance at NYU Abu Dhabi, on Sunday, October 17th, 2021 and facilitated by Lauren Kata, Assistant Academic Librarian for Archives and Special Collections at NYUAD. Conducted as part of The Memory Project.
    In this interview, Theresa shares about her journey to NYUAD, her contributions and experiences while working in the HR Office. She talks about her first impression of Abu Dhabi, the culture, people and climate, which are completely different from her previous workplaces back in London. She vividly recalls her first day at the Downtown campus and the warm welcome she received. She has fun memories of shifting to the Saadiyat campus and adjusting to new campus life. Theresa mentions the work she has accomplished, like the Saadiyat Social, hosting onboarding cultural orientation to the new staff and faculty, and employee service and recognition parties. Engaging, volunteering, and communicating with students is what excites her. Theresa, at the end, says she is very proud and happy for being part of NYUAD.
  - Interview session with Dustin Harris and Lauren Kata (01:15:20), 17 November 2021; ADRG023_071 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_071)
    Video-recorded session with Dustin Harris, Senior Designer in the Public Affairs and Communication Team at NYU Abu Dhabi, on Wednesday, November 17th, 2021 and facilitated by Lauren Kata, Assistant Academic Librarian for Archives and Special Collections at NYUAD. Conducted as part of The Memory Project.
    In this interview, Dustin shares about his journey to NYUAD, his contributions and experiences while working as a Senior Designer in the Public Affairs and Communication Department. He shares how he first heard about NYUAD and his earliest impressions of Abu Dhabi. He speaks about his initial roles and responsibilities of collaborating, helping and setting expectations of his team regarding designing and branding of the university at a crucial transitional phase of a growing global institution. Dustin outlines his work which has ranged from maintaining public websites, ad campaigns, to hosting large events like Commencement ceremonies, and Marhaba. He fondly remembers the entire creative work process, put together resulting in the creation of a meaningful logo and tagline for the 10th Year Anniversary celebration.
  - Interview session with Tegan McDuffie and Lauren Kata (01:35:14), 09 January 2022; ADRG023_072 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_072)
    Video-recorded session with Tegan Mc Duffie, Instructor of Project and Stage Management, recorded on January 9, 2022 and facilitated by Lauren Kata, Archivist and Assistant Academic Librarian. Conducted as part of The Memory Project.
    In this interview, Tegan describes how she got invited to be a stage manager for a production at NYUAD, which eventually led her to a full-time job. She explains her first impressions of Abu Dhabi, and then working at NYU Abu Dhabi on productions such as RealAD, but she also emphasizes best practices as an instructor and considerations around the cultural context of the country. She touches upon the important aspects of dealing with various equipment and how students have utilized equipment in their Capstone pieces. Tegan discusses NYUAD's signature theater programs and finally reflects on her personal experience and growth period while at NYUAD.
  - Interview session with John Pine and Lauren Kata (01:07:44), 24 January 2022; ADRG023_073 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_073)
    Video-recorded session, with John Pine, Director of Alumni Relations and Annual Giving at NYU Abu Dhabi, recorded on Monday, January 24, 2022, and facilitated by Lauren Kata, Assistant Librarian for Archives and Special Collections, NYUAD Library. Conducted as part of The Memory Project.
    In this interview, John Pine, talks about his experience at NYU Abu Dhabi as Director of Alumni Relations and Annual Giving between 2018 and 2022. Prior to joining NYUAD, Pine served as Director of Outreach Programs at the NYU office in New York for five years. He shares that he was impressed by the diverse multicultural environment offered at NYU Abu Dhabi. As a Director of Alumni Relations, he created a strategic plan for improving alumni engagement with a focus on 4 key areas: 1) alumni-to-alumni engagement through traditional methods (e.g., events, regional programs, career support); 2) alumni-to-student support via mentorship and advising; 3) communications and marketing (sharing alumni stories in different media, e.g. social media, website); 4) philanthropy. Pine also shares his memories from organizing reunion dinners for alumni to sharing alumni stories in different mediums, such as Beyond Saadiyat and a podcast in collaboration with the Career Development Center.
  - Interview session with Shamoon Zamir and Lauren Kata (01:49:03), 18 February 2022; ADRG023_074 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_074)
    [summary in process]
  - Interview session with Bryan Waterman and Lauren Kata (Part 1) (01:59:00), 31 May 2022; ADRG023_075 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_075)
    This is Session 1 of a two-session set of interviews conducted as part of Bryan Waterman's exiting NYUAD.
    Note: there are two recordings in this first session; the first recording is the bulk of the interview, and then a 4-minute epilogue was added to describe Bryan's Zoom background, which is an image of artwork that was special to him.
  - Interview session with Deborah Williams and Lauren Kata (01:49:23), 06 September 2022; ADRG023_076 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_076)
    Video-recorded session with Deborah William - Clinical Full Professor at the School of Liberal Studies of New York University and facilitated by Lauren Kata - Assistant Academic Librarian for Archives and Special Collections. Conducted as part of The Memory Project.
    In this interview, NYU affiliated faculty member Deborah Williams of the Literature and Creative Writing program delves into various aspects of her experience at NYU Abu Dhabi since the days of the Downtown campus. She highlighs student engagement and the evolution of the curriculum over time, as well as her involvement in initiating literary journals and community reading events. Williams also reflects on the residential aspect of campus life, sharing personal anecdotes about living accommodations and community dynamics. Additionally, she addresses pressing issues such as diversity, labor rights, and the quality of discourse within the institution, emphasizing the need for meaningful conversations and systemic change. Despite facing institutional challenges, Williams expresses appreciation for the extraordinary students and colleagues she has encountered at NYU Abu Dhabi.
  - Interview session with Justin Stearns and Lauren Kata (01:47:36), 21 June 2022; ADRG023_081 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_081)
  - Interview session with Bryan Waterman and Lauren Kata (Part 2) (01:20:54), 23 June 2022; ADRG023_082 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_082)
  - Interview session with Sebastian Grube and Lauren Kata (01:06:51), 24 June 2022; ADRG023_083 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_083)
    Video-recorded session, with Sebastian Grube, former Community Engagement and Marketing Officer at NYU Abu Dhabi Art Gallery, recorded on Friday, June 24, 2022, and facilitated by Lauren Kata, Assistant Librarian for Archives and Special Collections, NYUAD Library. Conducted as part of The Memory Project.
    In this session, Sebastian Grube shares his experiences at NYU Abu Dhabi as a member of the Class of 2018 and a former Community Engagement and Marketing Officer at NYUAD Art Gallery. Grube shares how he experienced Candidate Weekend at Sama Tower and witnessed the Saadiyat campus construction. He also shares that interacting with upper class students who had lived in Sama Tower enabled him to get to know and navigate around Abu Dhabi better. The multicultural setting and academic interdisciplinarity offered at NYUAD changed Grube's perspective on what it means to be a global leader and assisted him throughout his journey as a Music and Theater program double major student, and as Art Gallery Community Engagement and Marketing officer. Grube is now looking to continue his journey as an artist who brings artistic sensibilities into business context
  - Interview session with Judi Olson and Lauren Kata (01:44:44), 04 July 2022; ADRG023_084 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_084)
    Video-recorded session with Judi Olson, Instructor of Costume Design and Arts and Humanities Representative on the Academic Staff Committee of Staff Council at NYUAD, recorded on Monday, July 4th, 2022, and facilitated by Lauren Kata, Assistant Librarian for Archives and Special Collections, NYUAD Library. Conducted as part of The Memory Project.
    Judi Olson graduated from NYU's Tisch School of the Arts in 2009 and joined NYU Abu Dhabi in 2012. Between 2012 and 2016, Olson worked part-time on theater productions and joined NYUAD full-time in 2016. During her first four years, she worked on multiple student productions such as The Ramayana, The Aeneid, A Dream Play, and The Odyssey. In this interview session, Olson talks about the fluidity of the theater program and the transient nature of NYUAD, as well as the challenges and accomplishments of the past six years. Olson also shares nostalgic memories of the brunch culture in Abu Dhabi as a tradition of the expat community in the UAE, and her participation in the Abu Dhabi Choral Group.
  - Interview session with Lauren Kata and Jennifer McGlennon (01:51:11), 7 December 2022; ADRG023_085 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_085)
    Video-recorded session with Jennifer McGlennon, Former Vice Provost of NYUAD Graduate Programs, facilitated by Lauren Kata, Assistant Academic Librarian for Archives and Special Collections. Conducted as part of The Memory Project.
    Jennifer McGlennon provides a comprehensive overview of her role as the founding Assistant Vice Provost of Graduate Programs at NYU Abu Dhabi. She shares her background in academia and consulting, including her involvement in educational projects across Indonesia, Australia, and the UAE. McGlennon reflects on the cultural shifts she witnessed in the UAE, particularly in Dubai, where she previously spearheaded educational initiatives. The interview delves into the complexities of establishing graduate programs at NYUAD, highlighting negotiations with department chairs in New York and the challenges of harmonizing institutional cultures across NYU's diverse schools. McGlennon emphasizes the importance of aligning resources and policies to support the needs of PhD students and faculty members, navigating funding arrangements and support services for international scholars. Throughout the discussion, McGlennon underscores the collaborative efforts between NYUAD and stakeholders, including the UAE government and NYU's central administration. She discusses the role of strategic research projects in shaping academic offerings and fostering interdisciplinary collaborations, concluding by reflecting on NYUAD's evolution into a premier academic institution in the region.
- Citizen Archivist Memory Recordings [IN PROCESS], 2023-2024
- Alumni Reunion Recordings [IN PROCESS], November 2024